<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-02-18T23:30:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">71 North Partnership Studio</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Partnership builder Karinne Bredberg steps into new post as director of innovation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/09/22/post4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Partnership builder Karinne Bredberg steps into new post as director of innovation" /><published>2022-09-22T22:54:30-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-22T22:54:30-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/09/22/post4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/09/22/post4.html"><![CDATA[<p>It hasn’t been difficult for Karinne Bredberg to hit the ground running as NIU’s new director of innovation in the Division of Research and Innovation Partnerships (RIPS).</p>

<p>Bredberg’s education and professional experience have prepared her well.</p>

<p>She’s a double alumna of NIU, having earned a bachelor’s degree in biology and Master of Public Administration degree. She also has worked for RIPS in several capacities since 2006, most recently as assistant director in the Office of Innovation. She steps into the director post previously held by her collaborator Luke Sebby, who’s now in a new role with the NIU Foundation.</p>

<p>“Like so many of our amazing alumni, I have a special fondness for my alma mater and want it to thrive,” Bredberg says. “I take great pride in the work that our office does to fulfill the university’s mission and vision. At one time or another, I managed all aspects of our services, including the university’s intellectual property portfolio.”</p>

<p>Gerald Blazey, NIU’s vice president for Research and Innovation Partnerships, says Bredberg has been the go-to person when it comes to establishing partnerships that have led to opportunities for hundreds of students. She spearheaded past initiatives with Discover Financial Services and IDEAL Industries Inc., as well as a current internship program with Northwestern Mutual, which has taken up residence in NIU’s 71 North Partnership Studio.</p>

<p>“Karinne has really demonstrated the ability to forge innovative partnerships that benefit private industry and at the same time provide NIU students with incredible opportunities that lead to jobs post-graduation,” Blazey says. “In addition to being experienced in all facets of innovation, she’s a team player who works well with others. I know she’ll be able to build and expand on the growing success of our Office of Innovation.”</p>

<p>Developing more partnerships is among Bredberg’s priorities.</p>

<p>“I will be looking for those win-win opportunities that engage our NIU community in the advancement of research, innovation and entrepreneurship and enable students to translate classroom learning into real-world application,” she says. “These partnerships can form with external partners—but also inter-departmentally.”</p>

<p>Bredberg hopes to take full advantage of the 71 North Partnership Studio and its prime location on campus in Founders Memorial Library.</p>

<p>“Dean (Fred) Barnhart and the University Libraries administration have been a fantastic partner for the Office of Innovation and the Studio,” Bredberg says. “It’s a natural location fit for us since we both provide resources that stimulates the spark in people to create new ideas.”</p>

<p>The 71 North space already is getting plenty of use.</p>

<p>In addition to Northwestern Mutual, other industry tenants include Premier Crop Systems, a precision agriculture company; and 168 Community, an alumnus startup focused on educational enhancement opportunities for higher education students. The space also accommodates the STARS Faculty Academy; the student Innovation Club; the Innovation Conversations series; networking events known as Catalytic Conversations; ad-hoc innovation-centered meetings for other campus units; Office of Innovation facilitated events, including startup incubation; and Tuesday afternoon office hours for the Business Law Innovation Clinic, which provides legal assistance for commonly occurring issues in startup formation and company operations.</p>

<p>“The term ‘innovation’ encompasses a wide breadth of opportunities for our office to be involved in and develop around,” Bredberg says. “We’re fortunate to have an amazing community of forward-thinking students, faculty and staff who have creative and innovative ideas. So you could view the Office of Innovation as a facilitator—we help turn those ideas into realities.”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It hasn’t been difficult for Karinne Bredberg to hit the ground running as NIU’s new director of innovation in the Division of Research and Innovation Partnerships (RIPS).]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/post4.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/post4.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Fred Barnhart earns second term as NIU Libraries dean</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/05/04/post10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fred Barnhart earns second term as NIU Libraries dean" /><published>2022-05-04T22:54:30-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-04T22:54:30-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/05/04/post10</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/05/04/post10.html"><![CDATA[<p>NIU Libraries Dean Fred Barnhart, a champion of student success who played a key role in helping the university weather pandemic-related challenges, has accepted a second four-year appointment.</p>

<p>“I’m excited to continue our work as we demonstrate that University Libraries is much more than books on the shelf or databases on a website,” Barnhart said. “At its heart are dedicated staff and faculty with specialized training and degrees who acquire, curate and disseminate information and services on a daily basis throughout the year to support our institutional mission.”</p>

<p>Committed to student success, NIU Libraries went to extraordinary lengths during the most challenging periods of the pandemic to continue its many services for the Huskie community while offering additional technology supports to students.</p>

<p>Working with several other colleges and the Division of Information Technology, the library expanded its fleet of circulating laptops by more than 200 and began circulating hotspots as well. The effort required quick work to upgrade older laptops and development of new ways (including UPS) to get laptops into the hands of students. In addition, the provost’s office received an Illinois GEER grant that resulted in more than 200 new laptops for the library to put into circulation. For fall 2022, the library is purchasing another 100 laptops for students, with plans to continue the program into the future.</p>

<p>The pandemic also prompted the library to add tools, such as self-checkout machines, pick-up lockers and book-paging apps, which increased the independence of its patrons. “One of the things that the pandemic underscored is the benefit of self-service tools for our users,” Barnhart said.</p>

<p>Barnhart and Professor Jessica Reyman further coordinated a campus-wide group of leaders to leverage what was learned about remote work during the past two years. “After talking to colleagues at other institutions, it is clear that NIU is much more progressive in thinking about how to take advantage of lessons learned from the pandemic,” Barnhart said.</p>

<p>More recently, University Libraries successfully began development of its Learning Commons in the Founders Memorial Library. The one-stop shop enhances student success by gathering a wide variety of services all in one place, including writing assistance, research help, group studies and assistance with technology. With the support of Academic Affairs, the Learning Commons will start fall 2022 in a more inviting location on the first floor of the Founders Memorial Library.</p>

<p>“By hiring a Student Success Librarian, we have been able to better integrate library services and skills training into the student experience,” Barnhart said. “The position has also played a key role in fostering the Learning Commons and helping us partner with other units on campus, such as the Huskie Academic Support Center.”</p>

<p>The library partnered with the Center for Teaching and Learning (CITL) to help students defray some of their textbook costs. The Course Materials Affordability Task Force, spearheaded by Barnhart and Jason Rhode, CITL executive director and chief online learning officer, advocates for and supports the adoption of free and open textbooks and other low-cost course materials. The Task Force is co-chaired by Larissa Garcia and Tracy Miller and has grown to include faculty from several different colleges. The College of Liberal Arts and Sciences also helped the library support textbook affordability efforts with seed money, and many faculty members have donated their own course materials to the library. Not surprisingly, the initiative, managed by DeeAnna Phares, has proven popular with both students and faculty alike.</p>

<p>Barnhart’s first term also saw the creation of the library’s Diversity, Equity and Inclusion Committee (DEI) and the Programming and Promotion Committee. The DEI Committee has worked to make the libraries more accessible and inviting, and also seeks to revise policies to enhance equity. The Program and Promotion Committee was created to help the library formalize and coordinate efforts to promote library services, but also the scholarship and research of faculty and students. The committee has developed such programs as the annual Faculty Book Reception, Tuba Christmas cosplay events to celebrate the graphic novels collection, faculty photography exhibits and a tribute to famed cellist Raya Garbosouva.</p>

<p>The library has also developed partnerships with Research and Innovation Partnerships in the 71 North Partnership Studio and with Outreach Engagement and Regional Development. “We are lucky at NIU to be able to work with creative people outside the library to advance the same goals – student success and extending the impact of our faculty’s research,” Barnhart said.</p>

<p>One priority in Barnhart’s second term will be completion of the library’s strategic planning process. Goals will include maximizing student success through assessment and accountability, transformation of collections to meet evolving community needs, enriched user experiences, and increased awareness and visibility of library programs.</p>

<p>“We remain committed to keeping the library at the heart of the academic and student success experience,” Barnhart said.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[NIU Libraries Dean Fred Barnhart, a champion of student success who played a key role in helping the university weather pandemic-related challenges, has accepted a second four-year appointment.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/post10.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/post10.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Northwestern Mutual seeks interns for program on campus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/04/14/post2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Northwestern Mutual seeks interns for program on campus" /><published>2022-04-14T22:54:30-05:00</published><updated>2022-04-14T22:54:30-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/04/14/post2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/04/14/post2.html"><![CDATA[<p>Northwestern Mutual is taking up residence in the heart of campus, where the leading financial services company hopes to boost its university presence and expand its number of Huskie interns.</p>

<p>An Open House mixer introducing the company’s new space to faculty and students will be held from 4 to 6 p.m. Thursday, April 21, at the 71 North Partnership Studio, located in the lower level of Founders Memorial Library.</p>

<p>The company is seeking to fill internships for its top-rated program. Each year, the four offices which make up Northwestern Mutual Chicagoland manage as many as 80 interns from different universities.</p>

<p>Space in the 71 North Partnership Studio is being leased from the university to provide a place for NIU interns to work while at school during the fall and spring semesters (with summer internships located on company sites). Northwestern Mutual expects to have company leaders on campus to work with students twice per week.</p>

<p>“We’re thrilled to welcome Northwestern Mutual to our community of innovators at 71 North,” said Luke Sebby, NIU director of innovation partnerships. “These conveniently located internships will help our students gain practical, real-world experiences, as well as valuable networking opportunities with our community members.”</p>

<p>Juniors and seniors in any major are welcome to apply for the internships, although applicants will benefit from a background in finance, marketing or sales. Qualified applicants must be coachable, possess strong communications skills and be open to learning about financial planning.</p>

<p>On the job, the interns will “test drive the role of a financial representative” in helping clients achieve financial security. They will be provided with training, development and one-on-one mentoring.</p>

<p>“We’re aiming to have 10-plus NIU students utilizing this space throughout the academic year,” said Financial Advisor Jason Frano, managing director of the Northwestern Mutual office in Naperville.</p>

<p>“This is an opportunity for students to jumpstart their careers, while also having a hand in making the lives of their clients better,” he added. “Interns will learn all the ins and outs of financial planning from seasoned financial professionals.”</p>

<p>The company’s internship program has summer, fall and spring start dates. Students can intern for one semester or multiple consecutive semesters.</p>

<p>Northwestern Mutual is no stranger to NIU. The Fortune 500 company has partnered with NIU Career Services for more than five years and more recently with the Professional Sales Program in the College of Business. The company currently has one NIU intern, with six more slated to begin this summer.</p>

<p>“We are looking forward to growing our partnership in preparing students for their futures,” Frano said.</p>

<p>Karinne Bredberg, NIU’s assistant director for innovation operations, said the partnership demonstrates the talents and skills of Huskies.</p>

<p>“The desire to have an on-campus presence shows Northwestern Mutual’s commitment to its internship program,” she said. “It also reflects well on the strength of our students who have interned with them in the past.”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Northwestern Mutual is taking up residence in the heart of campus, where the leading financial services company hopes to boost its university presence and expand its number of Huskie interns.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/post2.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/post2.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">‘We all eat’ — Innovation Conversations’ all-star lineup will address sustainability issues</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2021/08/25/post5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="‘We all eat’ — Innovation Conversations’ all-star lineup will address sustainability issues" /><published>2021-08-25T22:54:30-05:00</published><updated>2021-08-25T22:54:30-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2021/08/25/post5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2021/08/25/post5.html"><![CDATA[<p>An all-star lineup of speakers is planned for NIU’s new series of Innovation Conversations, which launched last spring and brings in high-level experts to discuss sustainable food systems.</p>

<p>“Food systems affect everybody—we all eat,” says Bryan Flower, assistant director of food systems innovation for NIU’s Division of Research and Innovation Partnerships (RIPS). “It’s time to start learning more about what’s available to us, how we can be more sustainable, and how to make a difference in the world by the choices we make.”</p>

<p>Free and open to the public, the upcoming Innovation Conversations will be held in the 71 North Partnership Studio (in the lower level of Founders Memorial Library). Registration is required, and audience members have the option of attending in person or joining the events virtually.</p>

<p>Paul Lightfoot, founder and president of BrightFarms, will kick off the fall series with a discussion from 3 to 4 p.m. Thursday, Sept. 2, on controlled environment agriculture and the role it will play in the future of food systems.</p>

<p>BrightFarms builds and operates high-tech greenhouse farms, including one in nearby Rochelle, to eliminate time, distance and costs from its produce supply chain. Lightfoot has been leading the company since 2011 on its mission to provide consumers with the freshest, tastiest and most responsibly grown produce. BrightFarms was 235th on the 2017 Inc. 500 list of fastest-growing private companies.</p>

<p>NIU alumnus and Youtech founder and CEO Wilbur You, named to Forbes Magazine’s annual 30 Under 30 list, will discuss marketing strategies and entrepreneurism in food systems from 3 to 4 p.m. Thursday, Sept. 23.</p>

<p>Youtech integrates technology and marketing for businesses to make them more productive and successful in the 21st century. Headquartered in both Naperville and Scottsdale, Ariz., with plans to expand into Texas, Youtech services more than 1,000 clients, including MillerCoors, Chick-fil-A and 3M. With You as CEO, the company has been ranked in Inc.’s Fastest Growing Companies in the country for the past four years.</p>

<p>Mandi Lynn Kerr, CEO  and founder of the Global Hemp Association (GHA), will talk from 3 to 4 p.m. Thursday, Oct. 21, about hemp sustainability and its role in the food systems of the future.</p>

<p>GHA was founded to connect farmers, manufacturers, distributors and even regulators to advance hemp in textiles, food, biofuels, construction, education and sustainability. The association is the networker for hemp professionals.</p>

<p>The Innovation Conversation Series is sponsored by RIPS and the Northern Illinois Center for Community Sustainability (NICCS). Last spring’s conversations were well attended—and Flower expects the audiences to grow.</p>

<p>“We’re really hoping to draw more deans and faculty leaders from our different NIU schools, and more community members,” Flower said. “We’ll also be delving into more technology-related and intellectual-property topics, so you can expect the series to grow in its breadth as well.”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An all-star lineup of speakers is planned for NIU’s new series of Innovation Conversations, which launched last spring and brings in high-level experts to discuss sustainable food systems.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/post5.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/post5.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Workshop series: How to become an entrepreneur</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/02/17/post1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Workshop series: How to become an entrepreneur" /><published>2020-02-17T21:54:30-06:00</published><updated>2020-02-17T21:54:30-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/02/17/post1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/02/17/post1.html"><![CDATA[<p>Think you might have the spark of an idea for a clever invention? Ever wonder what it would be like to start up your own business? A series of upcoming NIU workshops might help you turn your dream into reality.</p>

<p>The NIU JobsPLUS program, in collaboration with the Division of Research and Innovation Partnerships (RIPS), is organizing the 71 North Entrepreneurship and Innovation Series for NIU students, faculty, staff and community members.</p>

<p>The series will feature workshops focusing on different aspects of entrepreneurship and innovation. All events are free and open to the entire NIU community, unless noted below. Advance registration is requested.</p>

<p>Workshop topics will include how to approach angel investors, alumni success stories, entrepreneurs and their own personal health, and local and regional entrepreneurial success stories.</p>

<p>Most of the events will be held in the 71 North Partnership Studio on the lower level of Founders Memorial Library, adjacent to Discover Financial Service’s code_orange collaborative space.</p>

<p>“We wanted to create a series of events that would appeal to students, faculty, staff and community members who are already engaged in entrepreneurship or innovation, as well as those who might want to learn more about it,” said Chad Glover, director of JobsPLUS. “We welcome all students and anyone from the community who is interested in attending.”</p>

<p>The 71 North Partnership Studio, set to be renovated later this year, is a dedicated space on campus designed to promote innovation, creativity and entrepreneurship among students, faculty and staff, said Karinne Bredberg, RIPS assistant director for commercialization and innovation.</p>

<p>“We envision the 71 North Partnership Studio as the place where the spark of creativity and innovation will happen on a regular basis,” Bredberg says. “We hope this series of workshops will help us get the word out on this space—not only to students but to the entire NIU community.”</p>

<p>The series also will allow NIU to introduce its partnership with Innovation DuPage (ID), a nonprofit organization that supports the entrepreneurial community in the western suburbs. ID is focused on nurturing entrepreneurs building startups, innovative brands and vibrant small businesses. The organization will be among the NIU workshop series presenters.</p>

<p>Scheduled events (more may be added) include the following:</p>

<p>5 to 6 p.m. Monday, Feb. 24, 71 North – Design Thinking for the Social Impact: A World Café Experience. For NIU students only. The Collegiate Association of Unreasonable Social Entrepreneurs will host a World Café-style discussion about the most pressing environmental and social issues facing our world. At the event, students will have the opportunity to participate in design-thinking, a process for creative problem-solving. Register in advance.
4:30 to 6 p.m. Tuesday, March 3, 71 North – Preparation for Angel Investors. Travis Linderman, managing director of Innovation DuPage, will talk about the common thread that ties all startups together—the need to secure funding. Approaching investors too early can burn bridges and waiting too long hurts chances of breaking into new markets. Linderman will speak to attendees on how to prepare for angel investment and venture capital. Learn how to prepare your pitch, avoid devil investors and more. Advance registration for the public is available with 71 North; students should register with JobsPLUS.
4:30 to 6 p.m. Tuesday, March 24, 71 North – Exploring Entrepreneurship. Travis Linderman, managing director of Innovation DuPage, will moderate a panel discussion with regional entrepreneurs building products, innovation brands and game-changing technology. Discussion will focus on each phase of launching a fast-growing business, and entrepreneurs will talk about how they attract talent, grow sales and raise early investment. The discussion will provide an opportunity to ask questions and learn from startup founders taking different paths to build their businesses. Advance registration for the public is available with 71 North; students should register with JobsPLUS.
6 to 7 p.m. Tuesday, March 31, 71 North – Aspiration to Entrepreneurship. Local entrepreneurs in business, technology, arts, education, health care and social justice will share their experiences of going from aspiration to entrepreneurship. The event will include an engaging panel discussion followed by Q&amp;A and networking. Advance registration for the public is available with 71 North; students should register with JobsPLUS.
5:30 p.m. to 8 p.m. Wednesday, April 8, 71 North – Be Your Own Boss: Alumni Entrepreneurship Panel. If you’ve ever dreamed of going into business for yourself, you can hear firsthand from some of NIU’s finest alumni entrepreneurs. Panelists include NIU alumnus and Board of Trustees Chair Dennis Barsema, ’77; Ralph Strozza, ’81; Nick Strozza, ’08; and NIUAA Board Member Kimberly Moore, ’01, M.M. ’04. This event is free to students; cost for other attendees is $10 in advance or $15 at the door. Advance registration for the public is available with 71 North; students should register with JobsPLUS.
5:30 p. m. to 7 p.m. Thursday, April 16, Barsema Hall Auditorium – Health, Well-being and Entrepreneurship. Hosted by Management Professor Tim Michaelis, this unique event will focus on the role of personal health in association with new venture creation. You’ll hear from world-leading experts, practicing entrepreneurs, community members and current students on how your personal health relates to starting and growing an entrepreneurial venture. Resources will be provided on the Chicagoland entrepreneurship ecosystem and how to get more involved in entrepreneurship at NIU. Advance registration for the public is available with 71 North; students should register with JobsPLUS.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Think you might have the spark of an idea for a clever invention? Ever wonder what it would be like to start up your own business? A series of upcoming NIU workshops might help you turn your dream into reality.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/post1.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/post1.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Military vet Luke Sebby named NIU innovation director</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/02/17/post6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Military vet Luke Sebby named NIU innovation director" /><published>2020-02-17T21:54:30-06:00</published><updated>2020-02-17T21:54:30-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/02/17/post6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/02/17/post6.html"><![CDATA[<p>Two U.S. Army combat tours of Iraq. Expertise in Arabic linguistics. Six years of civilian intelligence work with the U.S. Department of Defense. Official travel spanning Europe, the Middle East and East Asia. A leadership role in an applied research organization.</p>

<p>Suffice it to say, Luke Sebby brings a unique background to NIU.</p>

<p>Sebby, 40, of Winfield, began this month as director of NIU innovation partnerships and technology transfer.</p>

<p>The new position is charged with managing the 71 North Partnership Studio and developing the university’s external entrepreneurial relationships.</p>

<p>“Luke has an impressive background and will bring invaluable experience, energy and insight to NIU,” says Jerry Blazey, vice president for the Division of Research and Innovation Partnerships.</p>

<p>“He will promote strategic university-wide innovation relationships and entrepreneurship for students, staff and faculty—and the commercialization of their efforts.”</p>

<p>While Sebby has traveled the world, NIU represents a homecoming.</p>

<p>A graduate of Marmion Academy in Aurora, he pursued a career in national security starting with the Army, followed by civilian work in the D.C. region. He holds a master’s degree in international relations from Tufts University in Massachusetts, a bachelor’s degree from Drexel University in Philadelphia and an Executive Certificate in Strategy and Innovation from MIT.</p>

<p>For the past seven years, Sebby worked for the Virginia Tech Applied Research Corporation, most recently as vice president of operations and development.</p>

<p>In that post, he focused on sparking innovation between the U.S. Department of Defense and small businesses and academic communities. During his time there, he says, the nonprofit grew in profitability, with excess funds poured back into research and development. He’s no stranger to technology transfer, partnership building, spinout companies and commercialization of applied research.</p>

<p>This past year, Sebby and his wife Kathleen, a Michigan native, decided to return to the Midwest, where they would be closer to family.</p>

<p>“It was important for me to find a role where I could make an impact using my experience with academia, industry and the federal government,” Sebby says. “I want to help move the innovation needle, and I’m inspired by the vision of Jerry Blazey and President Lisa Freeman.”</p>

<p>Sebby believes his training in “red team” leadership will be an asset. Red teaming employs a form of devil’s advocacy—challenging plans, policies, systems and assumptions—in the decision-making process. “Weirdly, there’s a relationship between red teaming and the innovation process,” Sebby says. “With both, you have to ask the right questions.”</p>

<p>He also describes himself as data driven. Toward that end, his top priorities include an “innovation inventory” of the people, processes, technologies and infrastructure at NIU. He is studying similar institutions as well, to find best practices and lessons learned from successes and failures.</p>

<p>The inventory and case studies will inform innovation strategy, he says, including with the development of the planned Northern Illinois Center for Community Sustainability, which recently received $15 million in state capital funding. “The center brings exciting possibilities for multidisciplinary collaboration—including with government, other universities and industry—along with opportunities for students to apply what they’re learning,” Sebby says.</p>

<p>He steps into his new role at an opportune time.</p>

<p>The 71 North Partnership Studio, located on the lower level of Founders Memorial Library, is scheduled for a makeover, possibly as early as this summer. The space is dedicated to the promotion of innovation, creativity and entrepreneurship throughout the NIU community.</p>

<p>Sebby also will have a chance to rub shoulders with leaders in the NIU entrepreneurial community during this semester’s 71 North Entrepreneurship and Innovation Series, which will bring students, faculty, alumni and community members together for discussions on innovation.</p>

<p>Among the discussion leaders will be Travis Linderman, managing director of Innovation DuPage, an organization that supports the entrepreneurial community in the western suburbs. The university has a memorandum of understanding to collaborate with the nonprofit.</p>

<p>“NIU is not an island,” Sebby says. “It’s part of a broader ecosystem, connected to many different people, places and organizations, like Innovation DuPage and the Illinois Innovation Network. I’m looking forward to strengthening these connections and building new ones.”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two U.S. Army combat tours of Iraq. Expertise in Arabic linguistics. Six years of civilian intelligence work with the U.S. Department of Defense. Official travel spanning Europe, the Middle East and East Asia. A leadership role in an applied research organization.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/post6.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/post6.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Alumna Audrey Southard to deliver Jobs PLUS talk on communication styles</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2016/11/09/post7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alumna Audrey Southard to deliver Jobs PLUS talk on communication styles" /><published>2016-11-09T21:54:30-06:00</published><updated>2016-11-09T21:54:30-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2016/11/09/post7</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2016/11/09/post7.html"><![CDATA[<p>Audrey Southard, who earlier this year received the Distinguished Alumna Award from the NIU College of Business, will deliver the next Jobs PLUS professional development event, titled “What’s My Style? Learning to Communicate with Others.”</p>

<p>The event will be held at 1:30 p.m. Tuesday, Nov. 15, in 71 North of Founders Memorial Library, a new collaborative enterprise space being developed to foster student innovation and entrepreneurial initiatives. Students are encouraged to visit the Jobs PLUS website to register for the event.</p>

<p>Registration for the event will be accepted through Friday, Nov. 11. Students will be asked to complete a short questionnaire prior to attending, which will be emailed to them after registration.</p>

<p>This Jobs PLUS event will help individuals understand their own communication and personality styles, as well as the styles of others and how to best work together in a diverse environment.</p>

<p>Southard has been a human resources executive for more than 30 years. She retired as the senior vice president of business process engineering at Follett Corporation in 2014 to focus on her passions of working with college students and coaching business professionals.</p>

<p>She has invested in faculty research and innovation at NIU by establishing a faculty excellence fund in management. Southard also serves on the NIU College of Business Advisory Board and the Career Services Advisory Board for the University of Denver.</p>

<p>Southard began her career in human resource management at Nabisco, then spent 11 years in human resources at the Tribune Company before moving to Follett. By the time she was promoted to her senior vice president position, she was already leading the human resources, communication, procurement, facilities and loss prevention components for Follett’s largest division, Follett Higher Education Group (FHEG).</p>

<p>Southard is an active member of the Society for Human Resource Management (SHRM) and the Human Resource Management Association of Chicago (HRMAC) and presents frequently at conferences and trade shows.</p>

<p>Jobs PLUS regularly hosts free professional development events open to all NIU students. Through partnerships with employers, students could even be eligible to attend these events on paid work time. Jobs PLUS events qualify for Passport in the College of Business and Honors Engaged in University Honors.</p>

<p>To learn more about Jobs PLUS or future professional development events, visit the Jobs PLUS website or contact Chad Glover.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Audrey Southard, who earlier this year received the Distinguished Alumna Award from the NIU College of Business, will deliver the next Jobs PLUS professional development event, titled “What’s My Style? Learning to Communicate with Others.”]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/post7.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/post7.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Pilot program seeks to help faculty sharpen grantsmanship</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2016/10/28/post9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pilot program seeks to help faculty sharpen grantsmanship" /><published>2016-10-28T22:54:30-05:00</published><updated>2016-10-28T22:54:30-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2016/10/28/post9</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2016/10/28/post9.html"><![CDATA[<p>A new pilot program inspired by Professor Melani Duffrin aims to help NIU faculty to focus their research enterprises, foster interdisciplinary collaborations and sharpen their grant-writing skills.</p>

<p>The Division of Research and Innovation Partnerships (RIPS) will kick off its STARS Faculty Academy with informational sessions in early September. The academy is being patterned after Duffrin’s doctoral-level course on research positioning and grantsmanship (UHHS 750).</p>

<p>Duffrin, a professor of Interdisciplinary Health Professions, has an impressive track record in the external funding arena. Over the course of her career at NIU and other universities, she has secured more than $3.8 million in federal funding for her FoodMASTER initiative.</p>

<p>Duffrin and Luke Sebby, director of innovation partnerships and technology transfer for RIPS, are overseeing the academy. They’re seeking roughly 30 faculty members to participate in the pilot.</p>

<p>“Dr. Duffrin is experienced in grantsmanship training and has cultivated excellent relationships with federal funding agencies, and Luke Sebby leads our efforts to promote strategic innovation relationships and entrepreneurship,” RIPS Vice President Jerry Blazey said. “We think this program holds great potential for helping faculty to advance fruitful collaborations, build capacity in focused areas of research, and improve the likelihood of successful grant applications.”</p>

<p>The academy will help faculty identify and develop lines of research that are likely to attract external support—and will include fun events designed to foster camaraderie and build cross-disciplinary partnerships.</p>

<p>The informational sessions for interested faculty will be held from 12:30 to 2 p.m. Thursday, Sept. 2, and from 10 to 11:30 a.m. Friday, Sept. 3, at the 71 North Partnership Studio (in the lower level of Founders Memorial Library).</p>

<p>Beginning in October, program participants will meet throughout the academic year from 10 to 11:30 a.m. on the first Friday of each month. Optional lunch, bowling, field trips and other social activities will follow from 11:30 a.m. to 1:30 p.m. on each of those dates.</p>

<p>Among the topics to be covered in the academy:</p>

<p>Building infrastructure and multidisciplinary research teams.
Writing aims, identifying funding sources and contacting program officers.
Developing project rationale, collecting pilot data and demonstrating expertise.
Program and management planning.
Federal review panel meetings.
Budgeting and finance.
Research design and evaluation.
Other aspects of strong grant proposals.
“Grantsmanship is an art,” Sebby said. “The STARS Faculty Academy is all about exploring the art, sharing lessons learned and bringing researchers together to spark ideas.</p>

<p>“I view innovation on a continuum,” he added. “This feeds the inception point and helps researchers get inspired. Then we go to the next level, which is making it work. We think this program will have measurable effects.”</p>

<p>Social aspects of the STARS Faculty Academy, such as the bowling events and other get-togethers, are important, too, Duffrin said. They will allow faculty members, particularly from different disciplines and colleges, to get to know and inspire each other.</p>

<p>“We want to make it a fun and engaging academic experience that will help faculty be productive and motivated,” she said.</p>

<p>Duffrin, who arrived at NIU three years ago, began developing her FoodMASTER program in 1999. Six years later, she received her first Science Education Partnership Award (SEPA) from the National Institute of General Medical Sciences (NIGMS), part of the National Institutes of Health.</p>

<p>FoodMASTER has benefitted from three 5-year cycles of SEPA funding, totaling $3.6 million. The project also has been supported by the U.S. Department of Agriculture Higher Education Challenge Grants Program.</p>

<p>“The academy is designed to help faculty understand how to develop a focused area of research and to insert themselves into those research communities,” Duffrin said. “Our primary end goal is to have them submit successful grant applications, but the goals of the program really depend on what individuals want to take away. I think they can learn to be successful in many aspects of the research enterprise.”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new pilot program inspired by Professor Melani Duffrin aims to help NIU faculty to focus their research enterprises, foster interdisciplinary collaborations and sharpen their grant-writing skills.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/post9.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/post9.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">NIU alumnus and corporate communications expert Harlan Teller to deliver Nov. 2 Jobs PLUS event</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2016/10/28/post8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NIU alumnus and corporate communications expert Harlan Teller to deliver Nov. 2 Jobs PLUS event" /><published>2016-10-28T22:54:30-05:00</published><updated>2016-10-28T22:54:30-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2016/10/28/post8</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2016/10/28/post8.html"><![CDATA[<p>Harlan Teller, interim vice president of NIU’s Division of Marketing and Communications, will speak on the topic of leadership when he delivers the next Jobs PLUS professional development event.</p>

<p>The event will be held from 11 a.m. to 12:30 p.m. Wednesday, Nov. 2, in 71 North of Founders Memorial Library, a new collaborative enterprise space being developed to foster student innovation and entrepreneurial initiatives. Students are encouraged to visit the Jobs PLUS website to register for the event and other upcoming professional development opportunities.</p>

<p>Teller, an NIU alumnus, is on leave of absence from his position as a senior managing director for the strategic communications unit of FTI Consulting, having stepped down as vice chairman and chief knowledge officer of FD, the predecessor firm, in 2008.</p>

<p>He opened the firm’s Midwest operation in 2005 after a distinguished 30-year career in corporate communications at global PR giants Burson-Marsteller, Carl Byoir and Associates, and Hill and Knowlton (H&amp;K). His clients at these firms included such names as McDonald’s, Borg-Warner, Beatrice Foods, Sears, Ameritech, Allstate, United Airlines, Deloitte, Ernst and Young, AutoNation, Enron and Exelon.</p>

<p>“Most leaders are not born,” Teller says. “They learn on the job how to lead.</p>

<p>“Invariably, the professional skills that get you your first job and even your first several promotions don’t necessarily translate into the skills it takes to be a true leader of an organization,” he adds. “In fact, many of these skills—active listening, interpersonal communications, critical thinking, behavior modeling—are skills that can be gained from a liberal arts education, and in applying them to any job you may have.”</p>

<p>In this talk and question and answer session, titled “Crossing the Bridge from Doing to Leading,” Teller will define the skills needed to be a great leader. While he will use examples from his own career in corporate communications and public relations, the skills in these disciplines are translatable to other industries and professional services.</p>

<p>Jobs PLUS regularly hosts free professional development events open to all NIU students. Through partnerships with employers, students could even be eligible to attend these events on paid work time. Jobs PLUS events qualify for Passport in the College of Business and Honors Engaged in University Honors.</p>

<p>To learn more about Jobs PLUS or future professional development events, visit the Jobs PLUS website or contact Chad Glover.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harlan Teller, interim vice president of NIU’s Division of Marketing and Communications, will speak on the topic of leadership when he delivers the next Jobs PLUS professional development event.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/post8.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/post8.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Leadership development coach to deliver next Jobs PLUS talk</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2016/10/24/post3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leadership development coach to deliver next Jobs PLUS talk" /><published>2016-10-24T22:54:30-05:00</published><updated>2016-10-24T22:54:30-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2016/10/24/post3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2016/10/24/post3.html"><![CDATA[<p>NIU alumna and leadership-development coach Laura Hall will facilitate a Jobs PLUS event on the topic of “creating trusting and positive working relationships” at 5 p.m. Tuesday, Oct. 25, in 71 North of Founders Memorial Library.</p>

<p>The event is the first to be held at 71 North, a new collaborative-enterprise space being developed to foster student innovation and entrepreneurial initiatives.</p>

<p>While registration for the event is full, students are encouraged to visit the Jobs PLUS website to register for the remaining three Jobs PLUS events this semester at 71 North. Online registration is strongly encouraged.</p>

<p>Hall’s presentation will help participants surface and define the behaviors that they commonly exhibit at work and in different work situations or environments. Topics to be discussed will include:</p>

<p>Emotional intelligence and its role in creating positive relationships
How to show up in a more positive light despite difficult workplace cultures or environments
Leadership behaviors that help build trust
Using effective dialogue to strengthen workplace relationships
Jobs PLUS regularly hosts free professional development events open to all NIU students. Through partnerships with employers, students could even be eligible to attend these events on paid work time. Jobs PLUS events qualify for Passport in the College of Business and Honors Engaged in University Honors.</p>

<p>To learn more about Jobs PLUS or future professional development events, visit the Jobs PLUS website or contact Chad Glover.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[NIU alumna and leadership-development coach Laura Hall will facilitate a Jobs PLUS event on the topic of “creating trusting and positive working relationships” at 5 p.m. Tuesday, Oct. 25, in 71 North of Founders Memorial Library.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/post3.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/post3.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>